# TYLER C. WINSTEAD, B.S.

719-661-0645 • tyler.winstead6665@gmail.com GitHub: https://tywi6665.github.io • Portfolio: https://tywi.dev

## **QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY**

Dedicated and efficient full stack developer with experience coding in JavaScript and Python. Highly interested in creating functionally engaging, visually captivating, and web applications built upon React.JS, and Django. Thrives on troubleshooting, problem solving, debugging, and gleefully welcomes challenges. Additionally, I pride myself on being adaptable, comfortable working fast paced, and being deadline driven and devoted to learning.

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages (JavaScript, Python 3, HTML5, CSS3, SQL)
- Databases (MySQL, AWS S3, MongoDB)
- Libraries/Frameworks (React.JS, D3.JS, Express.JS, jQuery, NumPy, SciPy)
- Technologies (AWS Cloud Services, S3, REST APIs)
- Tools/Utilities (Anaconda, Jupyter Notebooks, Node.JS)
- Development Tools (Microsoft Visual Studio, GitHub, Adobe Creative Suite)

## **EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS**

University of Colorado Boulder • B.S. in Chemical & Biological Engineering • Boulder, CO
Pharmaceutical Biotechnology Focus
Minor in Biochemistry

December 2015

University of Denver • Web Development and Coding Bootcamp • Denver, CO

October 2018

Eagle Scout • Boy Scouts of America

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### UCAR COMET • Web Developer • Boulder, CO

August 2019 – Present

Casual August 2019 - April 2020

Full-time April 2020 - Present

- Acts as trainer and point of contact for COMET's Flash conversion project
- Drafts technical training documents to streamline and explain the Flash to HTML conversion process
- Familiar with varied climate and meteorological datasets and modeling strategies via HTML conversion of COMET's online education content
- Converts legacy Adobe Flash lessons to modern HTML5 web standards for COMET's Flash conversion project
- Conducts QA and code review of Web-based multimedia products to meet quality standards prior to publication
- Employs PHP and jQuery to create templates to be used in both HTML conversions and new lesson build

### Trilogy Education • Teaching Assistant • Denver, CO

October 2018 - December 2019

- Oversaw cohort of 25+ students
- Ensured students achieved thorough understanding of development lifecycle via one-on-one interaction
- Tutored students on the nuances of HTML, CSS, JavaScript and associated technologies and frameworks
- Gave constructive feedback on code and architecture
- Fostered collaborative dynamic built upon agile team development model